<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Segmentation Model: Creating a UNet architecture from ResNet50 as encoder</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</guid><description>In this post, I will be discussing a process of creating a UNet architecture where the encoder is sourced from the Resnet50. This technique is highly valuable, particularly when working with limited data, as it enables us to leverage the benefits of a pre-trained Resnet50 network. The UNet is an incredibly popular deep learning architecture for segmentation tasks and has become a go-to solution for many practitioners in this field. If you are interested in learning more about the original 2D UNet paper, I highly recommend referring to the source material.</description></item><item><title>3D UNet for Brain Tumor Segmentation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss how to use a 3D UNet to train a deep learning model. 3D UNet is a deep learning technique used for volumetric image segmentation, which is the process of dividing a 3D image into multiple regions or segments based on their characteristics. The architecture of 3D UNet is based on the popular 2D UNet, which has been widely used in biomedical image segmentation. If you want to read the paper of 2D UNet, visit here</description></item><item><title>3D Reconstruction Based on Medical Imaging For Personalized Surgical Procedures In Cardiac Rhythmology</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</guid><description>This is a short summary of my master thesis on VR at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris (IP Paris)
Abstract: Virtual Reality (VR) technology plays a vital role in Science and Engineering for immersive visualization and is a new interactive paradigm. The recent advancement in the processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of VR technology in medicine and surgery. Preoperative planning of Catheter Ablation (CA) Therapy in the VR environment is an important immersive application not only to minimize the risk of intricacy during surgery but also to reduce the operating time, a method of training for novice surgeons and for patient education.</description></item><item><title>Brain Tumor Detection with U-Net and Immersive Visualization in Mixed Reality Environment</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</guid><description>Problematics
The recent advancement in processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) technology in medicine and surgery. The visualization of human organs in the 3D environment takes a central role in the procedure of diagnosis and the follow up treatment of any disease. An automated immersive visualization of a human brain from a sequence of 2D MRI images in the MR environment is necessary not only to detect and classify the nature of tumors but also it helps surgeons to approach the tumor from a virtual perspective and to plan a possible surgery ahead of time.</description></item></channel></rss>