<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3D Reconstruction on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/3d-reconstruction/</link><description>Recent content in 3D Reconstruction on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/3d-reconstruction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marching Cube Algorithm</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/mc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/mc/</guid><description>Marching Cube Algorithm - an overview:
The Marching Cube Algorithm is a well known algorithm in computer graphics and scientific visualization for creating a 3D surface mesh from a 3D scalar field. The input of marching cube algorithm is a 3D voxels or 3D coordinate points and the output is a triangular mesh that represents the isosurface of the scalar field.
The basic idea of the algorithm is to divide the input volume into a regular grid of cubes, with each cube having 8 corners.</description></item><item><title>3D UNet for Brain Tumor Segmentation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss how to use a 3D UNet to train a deep learning model. 3D UNet is a deep learning technique used for volumetric image segmentation, which is the process of dividing a 3D image into multiple regions or segments based on their characteristics. The architecture of 3D UNet is based on the popular 2D UNet, which has been widely used in biomedical image segmentation. If you want to read the paper of 2D UNet, visit here</description></item><item><title>3D Reconstruction Based on Medical Imaging For Personalized Surgical Procedures In Cardiac Rhythmology</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</guid><description>This is a short summary of my master thesis on VR at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris (IP Paris)
Abstract: Virtual Reality (VR) technology plays a vital role in Science and Engineering for immersive visualization and is a new interactive paradigm. The recent advancement in the processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of VR technology in medicine and surgery. Preoperative planning of Catheter Ablation (CA) Therapy in the VR environment is an important immersive application not only to minimize the risk of intricacy during surgery but also to reduce the operating time, a method of training for novice surgeons and for patient education.</description></item></channel></rss>