<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/</link><description>Recent content on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Segmentation Model: Creating a UNet architecture from ResNet50 as encoder</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</guid><description>In this post, I will be discussing a process of creating a UNet architecture where the encoder is sourced from the Resnet50. This technique is highly valuable, particularly when working with limited data, as it enables us to leverage the benefits of a pre-trained Resnet50 network. The UNet is an incredibly popular deep learning architecture for segmentation tasks and has become a go-to solution for many practitioners in this field. If you are interested in learning more about the original 2D UNet paper, I highly recommend referring to the source material.</description></item><item><title>Solution of Poisson's equation over a polygonal domain</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/physics/poisson/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/physics/poisson/</guid><description>Poisson&amp;rsquo;s Equation
&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-
Poisson&amp;rsquo;s equation is a fundamental partial differential equation that arises in many areas of science and engineering. It is used to describe the behavior of scalar fields in physical systems such as electric potential or temperature distribution. The equation is expressed in terms of a source term and describes the distribution of the scalar field in a given physical system. Solving Poisson&amp;rsquo;s equation is a fundamental problem in many areas of research, including mathematical physics, engineering, and applied mathematics.</description></item><item><title>temas</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categoria/temas/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 23:21:18 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categoria/temas/</guid><description/></item><item><title>sintaxe</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categoria/sintaxe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 23:21:06 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categoria/sintaxe/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Códigos curtos</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/shortcodes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 11:51:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/shortcodes/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Biological Image Analysis using ImageJ</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ij/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ij/</guid><description>How to use ImageJ for biological image analysis
Image analysis is a critical step in many research fields, including biology, medicine, and materials science. One widely-used software for image analysis is ImageJ, which is a powerful, user-friendly program developed by the National Institutes of Health (NIH).
ImageJ allows users to analyze digital images by performing a range of quantitative measurements, such as area, intensity, and particle size. It also has a wide variety of image processing and manipulation tools, including filters, segmentation, and thresholding.</description></item><item><title>Second order Ordinary Differential Equation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/physics/ode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/physics/ode/</guid><description>Second-Order Ordinary differential equation (ODE)
&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;-
&amp;ndash;When a system is subject to a periodic forcing with a frequency that is equal to its natural frequency, it results in resonance. In forced oscillation, the frequency of the periodic force is denoted by \(\omega\) while the natural frequency of the system is denoted by \(\omega_{0}\). When \(\omega\) and \(\omega_{0}\) are equal, the amplitude of the oscillation increases significantly, leading to resonance. Resonance can be observed in a variety of physical systems, including mechanical, electrical, and acoustic systems.</description></item><item><title>Bayesian optimization of time perception</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/bayesianoptimization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/bayesianoptimization/</guid><description>Introduction: Context and Motivation
Humans are accurate at timing sub-second to minute intervals in daily routines, but their experience of time can be biased in different contexts. Traditionally, these biases were explained by the decay of modality-specific representations, changes in the internal clock speed, and memory mixing of different temporal representations. Recently, researchers have used Bayesian inference to analyze contextual calibration and improve performance, but how this links to temporal processing is unclear.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Dempster-Shafer Theory for Deep Learning</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ds/</guid><description>Introduction
The Dempster-Shafer theory (DST), named after its creators Arthur Dempster and Glenn Shafer, is a powerful mathematical framework for representing and managing uncertain information. It is particularly useful in situations where the available data is incomplete, imprecise, or contradictory. In this post, we will introduce the core concepts of the Dempster-Shafer theory, explore its practical applications in deep learning, and discuss its advantages over traditional probability theory.
Belief functions</description></item><item><title>Marching Cube Algorithm</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/mc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/mc/</guid><description>Marching Cube Algorithm - an overview:
The Marching Cube Algorithm is a well known algorithm in computer graphics and scientific visualization for creating a 3D surface mesh from a 3D scalar field. The input of marching cube algorithm is a 3D voxels or 3D coordinate points and the output is a triangular mesh that represents the isosurface of the scalar field.
The basic idea of the algorithm is to divide the input volume into a regular grid of cubes, with each cube having 8 corners.</description></item><item><title>3D UNet for Brain Tumor Segmentation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss how to use a 3D UNet to train a deep learning model. 3D UNet is a deep learning technique used for volumetric image segmentation, which is the process of dividing a 3D image into multiple regions or segments based on their characteristics. The architecture of 3D UNet is based on the popular 2D UNet, which has been widely used in biomedical image segmentation. If you want to read the paper of 2D UNet, visit here</description></item><item><title>AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/benchmark/</guid><description>This is my personal point of view on the AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark by Inioluwa Deborah Raji et al. The article can be download at AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark.
I think the paper was accepted for publication at NEURIPS 2021 as it highlights the risk of over-reliance of machine learning on benchmarking. Growing enthusiasm in North Star type dataset, which positions itself (or hyped by the ML communities) as benchmarks for &amp;ldquo;general purpose&amp;rdquo; visual object recognition or language understanding which in many ways, authors believe, creates undesirable consequences.</description></item><item><title>3D Reconstruction Based on Medical Imaging For Personalized Surgical Procedures In Cardiac Rhythmology</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</guid><description>This is a short summary of my master thesis on VR at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris (IP Paris)
Abstract: Virtual Reality (VR) technology plays a vital role in Science and Engineering for immersive visualization and is a new interactive paradigm. The recent advancement in the processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of VR technology in medicine and surgery. Preoperative planning of Catheter Ablation (CA) Therapy in the VR environment is an important immersive application not only to minimize the risk of intricacy during surgery but also to reduce the operating time, a method of training for novice surgeons and for patient education.</description></item><item><title>Brain Tumor Detection with U-Net and Immersive Visualization in Mixed Reality Environment</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</guid><description>Problematics
The recent advancement in processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) technology in medicine and surgery. The visualization of human organs in the 3D environment takes a central role in the procedure of diagnosis and the follow up treatment of any disease. An automated immersive visualization of a human brain from a sequence of 2D MRI images in the MR environment is necessary not only to detect and classify the nature of tumors but also it helps surgeons to approach the tumor from a virtual perspective and to plan a possible surgery ahead of time.</description></item><item><title>Human 3D Pose Reconstruction</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/pose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/pose/</guid><description>Human 3D Pose Reconstruction
This blog focuses on performing 3D reconstruction of human poses using multiple views captured by a calibrated system. To achieve this, a deep neural network called OpenPose is used to estimate the location of the joints in the human body. The OpenPose model has been trained to recognize 25 different joints in the human body, such as the head, shoulders, elbows, hips, knees, and ankles. These joints are critical for determining the posture and movement of a person.</description></item><item><title>Choregraphe Software for Pepper Robot</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/choregraphe/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/choregraphe/</guid><description>The purpose of this post is to build up a robot speaking system with body language and speech text and speech sound in Choregraphe. See the documentation here or download the software here.
The process is very straight forward using this software.
Step-1: Firstly we opened Choregraphe App and connected to the virtual robot &amp;lsquo;NAO H21​&amp;rsquo;. After that, we selected the &amp;lsquo;Say&amp;rsquo; node, ​&amp;rsquo;Delay&amp;rsquo; node and &amp;lsquo;Play Sound&amp;rsquo; ​node on the Box library.</description></item><item><title>Brain-Computer Interface for long-term memory management</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</guid><description>Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a field that aims to connect the human brain directly to a computer, allowing the transfer of information between the two. This technology holds tremendous potential to enhance human cognitive abilities in the future. The recent achievements of Neuralink, a startup founded by Elon Musk, have further fueled the excitement in this field. In a groundbreaking demonstration, Elon Musk showed the synchronization of a live pig&amp;rsquo;s brain with a computer, showcasing the viability of BCI technology.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing human abilities in the age of AI and VR.</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</guid><description>Visualizing a dream in the VR environment
Can we ever have the ability to visualize our dreams again after waking up? I often dream of re-watching my dreams after I wake up from sleep. Is this technologically feasible? What are the obstacles in building a system where a person can replay the dream they had last night? I plan to present a simple idea to illustrate this concept.
Dream visualization after waking up is an interesting and complex topic.</description></item><item><title>How did I feel about Windows 10 forced update?</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/windows10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/windows10/</guid><description>Dark Design Patterns is a phenomena in which values of users are undermined in favor of shareholder values. Designers and developers use this phenomena to exploit human psychology in order to increase/decrease/manipulate certain behaviors that are not in fact in favor of the end-users. Remember the Dark Design Patterns are not a simple error in design or an unintentional mistake. But they are accurately prepared with a deep understanding of human psychology with zero user&amp;rsquo;s interest in mind.</description></item><item><title>Gradient Decent, Stochastic Gradient Descent and Adam Optimization Algorithm</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/adam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/adam/</guid><description>Optimization Algorithms
Before we start the Adaptive Moment Estimation (Adam) optimization algorithm, we first see what is Gradient Decent (GD) optimization and how it works and then discuss about Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD) and finally Adam optimization.
Gradient Decent (GD)
GD is one of the most well known optimization algorithm available in machine learning and deep learning framework. Lets say we have a scalar cost function C which is continuous in the domain \(R_n\) (n-dimensional real vector space), takes the input vector \(x ( = x_1, x_2 &amp;hellip; x_n)\) of length \(n\) and we would like to find an optimal value of this cost function.</description></item><item><title>Keras – High Level API</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/kerasapi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/kerasapi/</guid><description>What is Keras?
It is a high-level neural network API, written in Python and able to running on top of TensorFlow. It is a very useful API, which enables us fast experimentation. Keras acts as an interface for the TensorFlow library. The task here is to study the image classification problem using notMNIST dataset. This dataset contains images of letters from A – J inclusive (dowload here). See the figure below to get an idea;</description></item><item><title>TensorFlow and the Low Level API - Part 2</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/fashion-mnist_tf2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/fashion-mnist_tf2/</guid><description>As a continuation from the previous part-1, in this post we will discuss a full multi-class classification problem (all 10 classes for Fashion MNIST). Using TensorFlow’s low level API (in graph mode) let us build a multi-layer neural network. We will define our architecture as follow:
Layer 1: 300 neurons (ReLu activation functions). Layer 2: 100 neurons (ReLu activation function) Layer 3: Softmax Layer Learning rate: 0.01 (with Gradient Descent). We will import the necessary libraries first;</description></item><item><title>TensorFlow and the Low Level API - Part 1</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/fashion-mnist_tf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/fashion-mnist_tf/</guid><description>What is TensorFlow?
TensorFlow is an open-source software library for dataflow and differentiable programming across a range of tasks. It is primarily used for machine learning and deep learning applications. TensorFlow provides a high-level API for building and training machine learning models, as well as a low-level API for defining mathematical operations. With TensorFlow, users can easily build, train, and deploy complex models on a variety of platforms, including desktops, servers, and mobile devices.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/about/</guid><description>I am a highly motivated and dedicated professional with a strong background in physics and a passion for artificial intelligence and virtual reality. I hold a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Physics, and my interest in deep learning and machine learning led me to pursue another Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in AI. I am a lifelong learner and I am always eager to acquire new knowledge and skills.
After completing my Master&amp;rsquo;s in AI, I decided to further my education and pursued another Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in VR.</description></item><item><title>How to create a static website using hugo?</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/websitewithhugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/websitewithhugo/</guid><description>Creating a website using Hugo is a straightforward process that can be broken down into a few simple steps. Why hugo?
Pros
No server side code Fast to render Often more secure Content is versioned Cons
No dynamic contents No database No real time UI etc Let us try out now;
Install Hugo: Before you can start creating your website, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to install Hugo on your computer. You can download the latest version of Hugo from the Hugo website (https://gohugo.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/contact/</guid><description>My physical location is:
Latitude: 46° N to 51° N Longitude: 6° W to 10° E Email me at: itubephysics@gmail.com</description></item></channel></rss>