<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personals on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personals on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/benchmark/</guid><description>This is my personal point of view on the AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark by Inioluwa Deborah Raji et al. The article can be download at AI and the Everything in the Whole Wide World Benchmark.
I think the paper was accepted for publication at NEURIPS 2021 as it highlights the risk of over-reliance of machine learning on benchmarking. Growing enthusiasm in North Star type dataset, which positions itself (or hyped by the ML communities) as benchmarks for &amp;ldquo;general purpose&amp;rdquo; visual object recognition or language understanding which in many ways, authors believe, creates undesirable consequences.</description></item><item><title>How did I feel about Windows 10 forced update?</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/windows10/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/personal/windows10/</guid><description>Dark Design Patterns is a phenomena in which values of users are undermined in favor of shareholder values. Designers and developers use this phenomena to exploit human psychology in order to increase/decrease/manipulate certain behaviors that are not in fact in favor of the end-users. Remember the Dark Design Patterns are not a simple error in design or an unintentional mistake. But they are accurately prepared with a deep understanding of human psychology with zero user&amp;rsquo;s interest in mind.</description></item></channel></rss>