<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Innovations on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/</link><description>Recent content in Innovations on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brain-Computer Interface for long-term memory management</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</guid><description>Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a field that aims to connect the human brain directly to a computer, allowing the transfer of information between the two. This technology holds tremendous potential to enhance human cognitive abilities in the future. The recent achievements of Neuralink, a startup founded by Elon Musk, have further fueled the excitement in this field. In a groundbreaking demonstration, Elon Musk showed the synchronization of a live pig&amp;rsquo;s brain with a computer, showcasing the viability of BCI technology.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing human abilities in the age of AI and VR.</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</guid><description>Visualizing a dream in the VR environment
Can we ever have the ability to visualize our dreams again after waking up? I often dream of re-watching my dreams after I wake up from sleep. Is this technologically feasible? What are the obstacles in building a system where a person can replay the dream they had last night? I plan to present a simple idea to illustrate this concept.
Dream visualization after waking up is an interesting and complex topic.</description></item></channel></rss>