<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machine Learning on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Machine Learning on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Segmentation Model: Creating a UNet architecture from ResNet50 as encoder</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/restnet/</guid><description>In this post, I will be discussing a process of creating a UNet architecture where the encoder is sourced from the Resnet50. This technique is highly valuable, particularly when working with limited data, as it enables us to leverage the benefits of a pre-trained Resnet50 network. The UNet is an incredibly popular deep learning architecture for segmentation tasks and has become a go-to solution for many practitioners in this field. If you are interested in learning more about the original 2D UNet paper, I highly recommend referring to the source material.</description></item><item><title>Understanding the Dempster-Shafer Theory for Deep Learning</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/ds/</guid><description>Introduction
The Dempster-Shafer theory (DST), named after its creators Arthur Dempster and Glenn Shafer, is a powerful mathematical framework for representing and managing uncertain information. It is particularly useful in situations where the available data is incomplete, imprecise, or contradictory. In this post, we will introduce the core concepts of the Dempster-Shafer theory, explore its practical applications in deep learning, and discuss its advantages over traditional probability theory.
Belief functions</description></item><item><title>3D UNet for Brain Tumor Segmentation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss how to use a 3D UNet to train a deep learning model. 3D UNet is a deep learning technique used for volumetric image segmentation, which is the process of dividing a 3D image into multiple regions or segments based on their characteristics. The architecture of 3D UNet is based on the popular 2D UNet, which has been widely used in biomedical image segmentation. If you want to read the paper of 2D UNet, visit here</description></item><item><title>3D Reconstruction Based on Medical Imaging For Personalized Surgical Procedures In Cardiac Rhythmology</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</guid><description>This is a short summary of my master thesis on VR at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris (IP Paris)
Abstract: Virtual Reality (VR) technology plays a vital role in Science and Engineering for immersive visualization and is a new interactive paradigm. The recent advancement in the processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of VR technology in medicine and surgery. Preoperative planning of Catheter Ablation (CA) Therapy in the VR environment is an important immersive application not only to minimize the risk of intricacy during surgery but also to reduce the operating time, a method of training for novice surgeons and for patient education.</description></item><item><title>Brain Tumor Detection with U-Net and Immersive Visualization in Mixed Reality Environment</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/unet/</guid><description>Problematics
The recent advancement in processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of virtual reality (VR) and augmented reality (AR) technology in medicine and surgery. The visualization of human organs in the 3D environment takes a central role in the procedure of diagnosis and the follow up treatment of any disease. An automated immersive visualization of a human brain from a sequence of 2D MRI images in the MR environment is necessary not only to detect and classify the nature of tumors but also it helps surgeons to approach the tumor from a virtual perspective and to plan a possible surgery ahead of time.</description></item><item><title>Brain-Computer Interface for long-term memory management</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</guid><description>Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a field that aims to connect the human brain directly to a computer, allowing the transfer of information between the two. This technology holds tremendous potential to enhance human cognitive abilities in the future. The recent achievements of Neuralink, a startup founded by Elon Musk, have further fueled the excitement in this field. In a groundbreaking demonstration, Elon Musk showed the synchronization of a live pig&amp;rsquo;s brain with a computer, showcasing the viability of BCI technology.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing human abilities in the age of AI and VR.</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</guid><description>Visualizing a dream in the VR environment
Can we ever have the ability to visualize our dreams again after waking up? I often dream of re-watching my dreams after I wake up from sleep. Is this technologically feasible? What are the obstacles in building a system where a person can replay the dream they had last night? I plan to present a simple idea to illustrate this concept.
Dream visualization after waking up is an interesting and complex topic.</description></item><item><title>Gradient Decent, Stochastic Gradient Descent and Adam Optimization Algorithm</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/adam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/adam/</guid><description>Optimization Algorithms
Before we start the Adaptive Moment Estimation (Adam) optimization algorithm, we first see what is Gradient Decent (GD) optimization and how it works and then discuss about Stochastic Gradient Descent (SGD) and finally Adam optimization.
Gradient Decent (GD)
GD is one of the most well known optimization algorithm available in machine learning and deep learning framework. Lets say we have a scalar cost function C which is continuous in the domain \(R_n\) (n-dimensional real vector space), takes the input vector \(x ( = x_1, x_2 &amp;hellip; x_n)\) of length \(n\) and we would like to find an optimal value of this cost function.</description></item><item><title>Keras – High Level API</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/kerasapi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/kerasapi/</guid><description>What is Keras?
It is a high-level neural network API, written in Python and able to running on top of TensorFlow. It is a very useful API, which enables us fast experimentation. Keras acts as an interface for the TensorFlow library. The task here is to study the image classification problem using notMNIST dataset. This dataset contains images of letters from A – J inclusive (dowload here). See the figure below to get an idea;</description></item></channel></rss>