<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Virtual Reality on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/virtual-reality/</link><description>Recent content in Virtual Reality on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/tags/virtual-reality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3D UNet for Brain Tumor Segmentation</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/3d-unet/</guid><description>In this post we will discuss how to use a 3D UNet to train a deep learning model. 3D UNet is a deep learning technique used for volumetric image segmentation, which is the process of dividing a 3D image into multiple regions or segments based on their characteristics. The architecture of 3D UNet is based on the popular 2D UNet, which has been widely used in biomedical image segmentation. If you want to read the paper of 2D UNet, visit here</description></item><item><title>3D Reconstruction Based on Medical Imaging For Personalized Surgical Procedures In Cardiac Rhythmology</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/projects/cardiac-rhythmology/</guid><description>This is a short summary of my master thesis on VR at the Institut Polytechnique de Paris (IP Paris)
Abstract: Virtual Reality (VR) technology plays a vital role in Science and Engineering for immersive visualization and is a new interactive paradigm. The recent advancement in the processing power of computers have enabled tremendous opportunities for the increased use of VR technology in medicine and surgery. Preoperative planning of Catheter Ablation (CA) Therapy in the VR environment is an important immersive application not only to minimize the risk of intricacy during surgery but also to reduce the operating time, a method of training for novice surgeons and for patient education.</description></item><item><title>Brain-Computer Interface for long-term memory management</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/memorymanagement/</guid><description>Brain-Computer Interface (BCI) is a field that aims to connect the human brain directly to a computer, allowing the transfer of information between the two. This technology holds tremendous potential to enhance human cognitive abilities in the future. The recent achievements of Neuralink, a startup founded by Elon Musk, have further fueled the excitement in this field. In a groundbreaking demonstration, Elon Musk showed the synchronization of a live pig&amp;rsquo;s brain with a computer, showcasing the viability of BCI technology.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing human abilities in the age of AI and VR.</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</guid><description>Visualizing a dream in the VR environment
Can we ever have the ability to visualize our dreams again after waking up? I often dream of re-watching my dreams after I wake up from sleep. Is this technologically feasible? What are the obstacles in building a system where a person can replay the dream they had last night? I plan to present a simple idea to illustrate this concept.
Dream visualization after waking up is an interesting and complex topic.</description></item></channel></rss>