<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bayesian Optimization on AI for HUMANITY</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categories/bayesian-optimization/</link><description>Recent content in Bayesian Optimization on AI for HUMANITY</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/categories/bayesian-optimization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bayesian optimization of time perception</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/bayesianoptimization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/posts/bayesianoptimization/</guid><description>Introduction: Context and Motivation
Humans are accurate at timing sub-second to minute intervals in daily routines, but their experience of time can be biased in different contexts. Traditionally, these biases were explained by the decay of modality-specific representations, changes in the internal clock speed, and memory mixing of different temporal representations. Recently, researchers have used Bayesian inference to analyze contextual calibration and improve performance, but how this links to temporal processing is unclear.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing human abilities in the age of AI and VR.</title><link>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://AIThoughtLab.github.io/ThinkingAI/innovations/dream/</guid><description>Visualizing a dream in the VR environment
Can we ever have the ability to visualize our dreams again after waking up? I often dream of re-watching my dreams after I wake up from sleep. Is this technologically feasible? What are the obstacles in building a system where a person can replay the dream they had last night? I plan to present a simple idea to illustrate this concept.
Dream visualization after waking up is an interesting and complex topic.</description></item></channel></rss>